YMCA ARMED SERVICES DEPARTMENT:
University of Minnesota Libraries
United Service Organizations-related records.
1932-1980
(bulk 1941-1950).
University of Minnesota. Kautz Family YMCA Archives. [ymca]
National Board of the Young Men's Christian Associations. Armed Services Dept.
Y.USA.4-2
Administrative files, club histories, and other records documenting the YMCA's involvement with the USO during and after World War II.
75.4 cu. ft. (130 boxes).
HISTORY OF YMCA ARMED SERVICES WORK WITH THE USO
The United Service Organizations (USO) was formed in the months before the United States entered World War II by a coalition of six civilian agencies to coordinate their civilian war efforts: the Salvation Army, Young Women’s Christian Association (YWCA), the Knights of Columbus, National Travelers Aid Association, National Jewish Welfare Board, and the Young Men’s Christian Association (YMCA). The YMCA and other welfare agencies had already been seeking ways to serve the morale needs of the increasing number of young men entering military training. With the September 1940 enactment of the Selective Service and Training Act, the military buildup accelerated, but the federal government had no plan for the provision of recreation facilities and activities in training camp communities. After a series of conference between representatives of the six welfare organization and several government agencies, a plan of cooperation was worked out with the endorsement of the President, the Secretary of War, the Secretary of the Navy, and the Federal Security Administrator. In January, 1941, the USO was incorporated to provide religious, recreational, welfare, and educational activities for men and women in the armed forces and in the defense industries. By the time of the United States' entry into the war in December, the USO had opened 139 clubs and 35 other units located in 98 towns and cities throughout the country.
The YMCA's contributions to the establishment of the USO and to its performance as a war-service organization were of major importance. With its experience in previous wars, the YMCA brought crucial resources to the new organization's start-up efforts, including a history of good relations with the officers and enlisted men of the Army and Navy, long experience mobilizing volunteers, buildings, and endowment funding. At the time the USO was incorporated, the YMCA already had 69 Army and Navy branches and other operations in place, staffed by 135 professional workers. Many of these operations could be immediately turned over to the joint enterprise as "ready-made" USO clubs. At the peak period in 1944, the YMCA Army and Navy Department had under its administration 464 USO operations (not including the sixty USO industrial units which were under the direction of the YMCA's Industrial Department). During the period from 1942 to 1947, nearly 460,000,000 visits were made to the YMCA-operated USO clubs and Army and Navy branches.
Offerings were varied and included religious programs, forums, lectures, athletics, parties, dances, dramatics, movies, sightseeing, and special events. Also available were personal services such as counseling, and help with matters such as housing, travel, community resources, locating persons, etc. Facilities and equipment provided included showers, swimming, shaving, sports, art, handicraft, photography, games, music, records, dormitories, gymnasiums, and more. In keeping with its historic concern for the religious needs of individuals, the YMCA offered chapel services, fostered relations with local churches and clergy, and developed a program to distribute religious, patriotic, and educational literature prepared especially for the men in the armed forces. The organization also designed a program of counseling seminars to assist ministers, chaplains and USO staff in dealing helpfully with the needs of servicemen.
In recognition of the significant work of the YMCA during the war years, the War and Navy Departments presented it in 1946 with a citation praising its patriotic service and calling its contribution "of substantial aid in the successful prosecution of the war and in preserving the basic values of American democracy."
Historical information was primarily excerpted from Serving the U.S. Armed Forces, 1861-1986: The Story of the YMCA's Ministry to Military Personnel for 125 Years, by Richard C. Lancaster.
SCOPE AND CONTENTS OF THE COLLECTION
Materials in this collection include club histories and photographs of both Army/Navy and industrial USOs, administrative files, information on associated organizations, miscellaneous records of individual USO clubs, and print materials. Records of Army/Navy and industrial clubs for African Americans, which were run as separate facilities, are also included. At the time, these USOs were known as "negro" clubs.
The club histories comprise the bulk of collection; an official history was created for each USO club at its closing, which includes board minutes, newspaper clippings and other information about the organization. This material is organized alphabetically by location of the club. Additional records of individual clubs can be found in the local club files within the general files series. Since many of these USOs were operated in Army/Navy YMCA facilities, overlap exists with material in the separately cataloged Armed Services Department records (see the "city files" series). Newsletters and other publications of individual USO clubs can be found in the print materials series.
Administrative records in the collection include reports, memoranda, correspondence, and topical files, as well as publications and other material from the five other organizations that comprised the USO, particularly the National Jewish Welfare Board, the National Catholic Community Service and the Salvation Army.
ORGANIZATION/ARRANGEMENT OF THE RECORDS
These documents are organized into the following sections:
Club Histories.
Administrative Files.
ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION
DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE COLLECTION
The following section contains a detailed list of the materials in the collection. To request materials, please note the corresponding box number.
- Club Histories
  - Industrial Clubs:
    Historical information on clubs which served people working in the war-related industries.
    - Childersburg, AL, 1941-1945.; 4 folders. (Box 1)
    - Gadsden, AL, 1943-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 1)
    - Huntsville, AL, 1944-1945. (Box 1)
    - Mobile, AL, 1942-1945. (Box 1)
    - Mobile, AL (African American), 1943-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 2)
    - Sheffield, AL, 1942-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 2)
    - Talledega, AL, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 2)
    - West Huntsville, AL, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 3)
    - Miami, AZ, 1945. (Box 3)
    - Phoenix, AZ, 1943-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 3)
    - Chula Vista, CA, undated.; 2 folders. (Box 4)
    - Campton, CA, undated. (Box 4)
    - Herlong, CA., 1945-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 4)
    - Inglewood, CA, 1941-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 4)
    - Inglewood, CA, 1941-1946. (Box 5)
    - Linda Vista, CA, 1944. (Box 5)
    - Long Beach, CA, 1943-1944.; 4 folders. (Box 5)
    - Long Beach, CA (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 5)
    - Los Angeles, CA, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 6)
    - Richmond, CA, 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 6)
    - San Diego, CA, 1943-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 6)
    - San Diego, CA, 1943-1945.; 8 folders. (Box 7)
    - San Diego, CA, 1943-1945. (Box 8)
    - Vallejo, CA, 1943-1946.; 5 folders. (Box 8)
    - Groton, CT, 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 8)
    - Wilmington, DE, 1943-1944. (Box 8)
    - Key West, FL, 1944-1946. (Box 9)
    - Panama City, FL, 1943-1946. (Box 9)
    - Savannah, GA, 1943-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 9)
    - Savannah, GA (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 9)
    - Warner Robins, GA, 1943-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 9)
    - Wilmington, IL, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 10)
    - Jeffersonville, IN, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 10)
    - Knox, IN, 1943-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 10)
    - Burlington, IA, 1941-1942. (Box 10)
    - Parsons, KS, 1942-1944. (Box 11)
    - Wichita, KS, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 11)
    - Wichita, KS (African American), undated. (Box 11)
    - Lake Charles, LA, 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 12)
    - Baton Rouge, LA, 1942-1945.; 5 folders. (Box 12)
    - Bath, ME, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 12)
    - Bath, ME, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 13)
    - Portland, ME, 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 13)
    - Portland, ME (African American), 1944-1946. (Box 13)
    - Dundalk, MD, 1942-1944.; 3 folders. (Box 13)
    - Lowell, MA, 1941-1942. (Box 14)
    - Quincy, MA, 1942-1943. (Box 14)
    - Van Dyke, MI, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 14)
    - Pascagoula, MS, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 14)
    - Fremont, NE, 1943-1944. (Box 14)
    - Manchester, NH, 1941-1942. (Box 15)
    - Portsmouth, NH, 1941-1945.; 4 folders. (Box 15)
    - Mineville, NY, 1943. (Box 15)
    - Rome, NY, 1942-1943. (Box 15)
    - Schenectady, NY, 1943. (Box 15)
    - Sidney, NY, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 16)
    - Burlington, NC, 1943-1944. (Box 16)
    - Wilmington, NC, 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 16)
    - Newton Falls, OH, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 16)
    - Osborn, OH, 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 16)
    - Ravenna, OH, 1942-1944.; 3 folders. (Box 17)
    - Vandalia, OH, 1943-1944. (Box 17)
    - Pryor, OK, 1942-1944. (Box 17)
    - Hermiston, OR, 1943. (Box 17)
    - Allegheny County, PA (Pittsburgh), 1941-1944.; 4 folders. (Box 17)
    - Chester, PA, 1942-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 18)
    - Middletown, PA, 1942-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 18)
    - North Charleston, SC, 1944-1946. (Box 18)
    - North Charleston, SC (African American), 1944-1946. (Box 18)
    - Knoxville, TN, 1944-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 19)
    - Knoxville, TN (African American), 1944-1946. (Box 19)
    - Borger, TX, 1944-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 19)
    - Freeport, TX, 1942-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 19)
    - Orange, TX, 1943-1945.; 5 folders. (Box 20)
    - Texarkana, TX (African American), 1943-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 20)
    - Texas City, TX, 1944-1945. (Box 20)
    - Texas City, TX, 1944-1945. (Box 21)
    - Ogden, UT, 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 21)
    - Burlington, VT, 1944. (Box 21)
    - Dublin, VA, 1942-1943. (Box 21)
    - Fort Royal, VA, 1944-1945. (Box 21)
    - Hampton, VA, 1943-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 21)
    - Newport News, VA, 1943-1945.; 5 folders. (Box 22)
    - Newport News, VA (African American), 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 22)
    - Portsmouth, VA, 1941-1946.; 7 folders. (Box 23)
    - Port Orchard, WA, 1944-1946. (Box 24)
    - South Central WA, 1945-1946. (Box 24)
    - Baraboo, WI, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 24)
    - Point Pleasant, WV, 1943. (Box 24)
  - Army-Navy Clubs:
    Historical information on clubs that served individuals in the armed forces.
    - Birmingham, AL, 1943-1947. (Box 25)
    - Birmingham, AL (African American), 1944-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 25)
    - Dothan, AL (African American), 1944-1945. (Box 25)
    - Gadsden, AL (African American), 1944-1946. (Box 25)
    - Montgomery, AL, 1941-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 76)
    - Montgomery, AL (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 76)
    - Ozark, AL, 1943-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 76)
    - Selma, AL (African American), 1943-1946. (Box 25)
    - Tuskeegee, AL (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 25)
    - Blytheville, AR, 1942-1945. (Box 25)
    - Blytheville, AR (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 25)
    - Fort Smith, AR, 1942-1946. (Box 26)
    - Fort Smith, AR (African American), 1942-1943. (Box 26)
    - Little Rock, AR, 1941-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 26)
    - Little Rock, AR (African American), 1942-1944. (Box 26)
    - Stuttgart, AR (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 26)
    - Walnut Ridge, AR, 1942-1945. (Box 26)
    - Douglas, AZ, 1942-1946. (Box 26)
    - Florence, AZ, 1942-1944. (Box 27)
    - Fort Huachuca, AZ (African American), 1941-1946. (Box 27)
    - Gila Bend, AZ, 1943-1945. (Box 27)
    - Tucson, AZ (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 27)
    - Yuma, AZ, 1944-1945. (Box 27)
    - Yuma, AZ (African American), 1943-1946. (Box 27)
    - Coronado, CA, 1944-1947.; 3 folders. (Box 27)
    - Enterprise, CA (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 27)
    - Fairfield, CA, 1953-1956. (Box 27)
    - Fresno, CA, 1943-1946. (Box 27)
    - Hanford, CA, 1942-1945. (Box 28)
    - Hollywood, CA, 1945-1946. (Box 28)
    - La Jolla, CA, 1941-1945. (Box 28)
    - Lemoore and Hanford, CA, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 28)
    - Long Beach, CA, 1943-1945.; 3 folders. (Box 28)
    - Marysville, CA, 1943-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 28)
    - Merced, CA (African American), 1943. (Box 28)
    - Monterey, CA, 1941-1947.; 3 folders. (Box 76)
    - Monterey, CA, 1941-1946.; 4 folders. (Box 29)
    - Monterey, CA (African American), 1942-1947. (Box 29)
    - Needles, CA, 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 76)
    - Oakland, CA (African American), 1942-1946.; 6 folders. (Box 77)
    - Oceanside, CA, 1949-1950.; 3 folders. (Box 29)
    - Paso Robles, CA, 1941-1946.; 4 folders. (Box 77)
    - Pittsburgh, CA, 1944-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 29)
    - Pittsburgh, CA, 1944-1947. (Box 30)
    - Pittsburgh, CA (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 30)
    - Riverside, CA, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 30)
    - Riverside, CA (African American), 1943-1944. (Box 30)
    - San Bernadino, CA (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 30)
    - San Diego, CA (African American), 1942-1957. (Box 30)
    - San Francisco, CA (African American), 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 30)
    - San Luis Obispo, CA, 1941-1946. (Box 30)
    - Santa Ana, CA, 1942-1951. (Box 30)
    - Santa Maria, CA, 1941-1946. (Box 31)
    - Stockton, CA, 1942-1945. (Box 31)
    - Stockton, CA (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 31)
    - Ventura, CA, 1942-1946. (Box 31)
    - Watsonville, CA, 1943-1945. (Box 31)
    - Watts, CA (African American), 1943-1947. (Box 31)
    - Wilmington, CA, 1943-1945. (Box 31)
    - Colorado Springs, CO, 1942-1944. (Box 31)
    - Denver, CO, 1945-1947. (Box 31)
    - Denver, CO, 1945-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 32)
    - Denver, CO (African American), 1944-1947. (Box 32)
    - Glenwood Springs, CO, 1943-1945. (Box 32)
    - La Juanita, CO, 1942-1946. (Box 32)
    - Pueblo, CO, 1942-1945. (Box 32)
    - Groton, CT, 1945. (Box 32)
    - New London, CT, 1941-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 77)
    - New London, CT, 1941-1946. (Box 78)
    - Niantic, CT, 1942-1945. (Box 32)
    - Washington, D.C., 1944-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 32)
    - Washington, D.C., 1946-1947. (Box 33)
    - Washington, D.C., 1736 G St., 1942-1947.; 6 folders. (Box 33)
    - Washington, D.C. 12th St. (African American), 1945-1950. (Box 33)
    - Anacostia, D.C., 1943-1945. (Box 33)
    - Washington, D.C., Georgia Ave. (African American), 1943-1947. (Box 33)
    - Wilmington, DE, 1941-1942. (Box 33)
    - Wilmington, DE, 1943-1947.; 3 folders. (Box 34)
    - Delray Beach, FL, 1942-1947.; 4 folders. (Box 34)
    - Fort Pierce, FL, 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 34)
    - Green Cove Springs, FL (African American), 1946-1947. (Box 35)
    - Homestead, FL, 1943-1944. (Box 35)
    - Jacksonville, FL, 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 35)
    - Key West, FL, 1940-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 35)
    - Key West, FL (African American), 1943-1946. (Box 35)
    - Leesburg, FL, 1944-1945. (Box 35)
    - Marianna, FL, 1942-1944.; 2 folders. (Box 35)
    - Marianna, FL (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 35)
    - Miami, FL, 1943-1947. (Box 35)
    - Miami, FL (African American), 1944-1945. (Box 35)
    - Milton, FL (African American), 1944-1945. (Box 36)
    - Panama City, FL (African American), 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 78)
    - Pensacola, FL, 1940-1950. (Box 36)
    - Pensacola, FL, 1942-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 78)
    - Sebring, FL, 1942-1946. (Box 36)
    - St. Augustine, FL, 1943-1946. (Box 36)
    - Starke, FL, 1942-1945. (Box 36)
    - Starke, FL (African American), 1941-1944. (Box 36)
    - Tallahassee, FL, 1943-1945. (Box 36)
    - Tallahassee, FL (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 36)
    - Tampa, FL, 1941-1946. (Box 37)
    - Valpariso, FL, 1945-1949.; 3 folders. (Box 37)
    - Venice, FL, 1943-1945. (Box 37)
    - Brunswick, GA, 1942-1945. (Box 37)
    - Columbus, GA, 1945-1947.; 3 folders. (Box 37)
    - Hinesville, GA, 1941-1953.; 3 folders. (Box 38)
    - Hinesville, GA (African American), 1941-1945. (Box 38)
    - Macon, GA, 1942-1945.; 4 folders. (Box 38)
    - Moultrie, GA, 1943-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 78)
    - Savannah, GA, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 38)
    - Savannah, GA (African American), 1943-1944. (Box 38)
    - Thomasville, GA, 1943-1945. (Box 38)
    - Thomasville, GA (African American), 1944-1945. (Box 38)
    - Toccoa, GA, 1942-1946. (Box 39)
    - Valdosta, GA, 1943-1953.; 2 folders. (Box 39)
    - Iowa City, IA, 1943-1945. (Box 39)
    - Sergeant Bluff, IA, 1943-1945. (Box 39)
    - Coeur D'Alene, ID, 1943-1945. (Box 39)
    - Mountain Home, ID, 1943-1946. (Box 78)
    - Sand Point, ID, 1942-1946. (Box 39)
    - Belleville, IL, 1941-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 39)
    - Canton, IL, 1943-1945. (Box 39)
    - Waukegan, IL (Great Lakes Naval Training Station), 1927-1940. (Box 39)
    - Highland Park, IL, 1941-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 40)
    - Lawrenceville, IL, 1942-1945. (Box 40)
    - Macomb, IL, 1943-1946. (Box 40)
    - Macomb, IL (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 40)
    - Peoria, IL, 1943-1945. (Box 78)
    - Rantoul, IL, 1941-1949. (Box 40)
    - Rockford, IL, 1942-1944.; 2 folders. (Box 40)
    - Waukegan, IL, 1940-1950.; 2 folders. (Box 41)
    - Waukegan, IL (African American), 1943-1946. (Box 41)
    - Edinburg, IN, 1942-1946. (Box 41)
    - Evansville, IN (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 41)
    - Franklin, IN, 1942-1945. (Box 41)
    - Peru, IN, 1942-1945. (Box 78)
    - Coffeyville, KS, 1942-1945. (Box 41)
    - Great Bend, KS, 1943-1946. (Box 41)
    - Great Bend, KS, 1943-1946. (Box 42)
    - Hutchinson, KS, 1942-1946. (Box 42)
    - Junction City, KS, 1949-1953. (Box 42)
    - Manhattan, KS, 1941-1946.; 4 folders. (Box 42)
    - Manhattan, KS (African American), 1941-1945. (Box 42)
    - Salina, KS, 1942-1949.; 2 folders. (Box 42)
    - Salina, KS, 1942-1949.; 2 folders. (Box 43)
    - Salina, KS (African American), 1943-1947. (Box 43)
    - Topeka, KS, 1941-1947. (Box 43)
    - Topeka, KS (African American), 1941-1946. (Box 43)
    - Wichita, KS, 1941-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 43)
    - Wichita, KS (African American), 1946. (Box 43)
    - Winfield, KS, 1943-1946. (Box 43)
    - Elizabethtown, KY, 1942-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 43)
    - Henderson, KY, 1942-1945. (Box 43)
    - Hopkinsville, KY, 1943-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 44)
    - Hopkinsville, KY (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 44)
    - Lexington, KY, 1943-1945. (Box 44)
    - Louisville, KY, 1943-1946. (Box 44)
    - Louisville, KY (African American), 1941-1946. (Box 44)
    - Morganfield, KY, 1943. (Box 78)
    - Lake Charles, LA, 1941-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 44)
    - Leesville, LA, 1941-1954.; 2 folders. (Box 44)
    - Leesville, LA (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 45)
    - New Orleans, LA, 1942-1947. (Box 78)
    - New Orleans, LA, 1942-1947.; 5 folders. (Box 79)
    - Shreveport, LA, 1942-1947.; 3 folders. (Box 45)
    - Shreveport, LA (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 45)
    - Chicopee Falls, MA, 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 45)
    - Falmouth, MA, 1943-1946. (Box 45)
    - Hyannis, MA, 1941-1945. (Box 45)
    - Hyannis, MA, 1941-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 46)
    - Mashpee, MA, 1941-1944. (Box 46)
    - Northampton, MA, 1947-1948. (Box 79)
    - Quincy, MA, 1942-1946. (Box 46)
    - Tauton, MA, 1942-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 46)
    - Tauton, MA (African American), 1943-1943. (Box 46)
    - Wetover Air Force Base, MA, 1948-1950. (Box 46)
    - Annapolis, MD, 1948-1951. (Box 46)
    - Annapolis, MD, 1948-1951.; 3 folders. (Box 47)
    - Havre de Grace, MD (African American), 1942-1947. (Box 47)
    - Laurel, MD, 1942-1945. (Box 47)
    - Eastport, ME, 1942-1945. (Box 47)
    - Portland, ME (African American), 1943-1947. (Box 47)
    - Sault Ste Marie, MI (African American), 1942-1943. (Box 47)
    - Carthage, MO, 1943-1946. (Box 47)
    - Joplin, MO, 1942-1946. (Box 47)
    - Joplin, MO (African American), 1944-1946. (Box 48)
    - Lebanon, MO, 1941-1946. (Box 48)
    - Neosho, MO, 1942-1945. (Box 79)
    - Rolla, MO, 1941-1942. (Box 48)
    - Sedalia, MO, 1943-1946. (Box 48)
    - St. Louis, MO, 1941-1945. (Box 48)
    - St. Louis, MO (African American), 1941. (Box 48)
    - Waynesville, MO (African American), 1941-1943. (Box 48)
    - Biloxi, MS, 1942-1947. (Box 48)
    - Biloxi, MS (African American), 1943-1947. (Box 48)
    - Centerville, MS, 1943-1945. (Box 49)
    - Columbus, MS, 1942-1945. (Box 49)
    - Flora, MS, 1943-1945. (Box 49)
    - Greenwood, MS, 1943-1946. (Box 49)
    - Grenada, MS, 1942-1945. (Box 49)
    - Grenada, MS (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 49)
    - Hattiesburg, MS, 1940-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 49)
    - Hattiesburg, MS, 1940-1946. (Box 50)
    - Hattiesburg, MS (Japanese-American), 1943-1945.; 2 folders. (Box 50)
    - Hattiesburg, MS (African American), 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 50)
    - Jackson, MS, 1945. (Box 50)
    - Jackson, MS (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 50)
    - Meridian, MS, 1942-1946. (Box 50)
    - Meridian, MS (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 50)
    - Winona, MS (African American), 1944-1946. (Box 50)
    - Helena, MT, 1943-1945. (Box 51)
    - Carolina Beach, NC, 1942-1944. (Box 51)
    - Durham, NC, 1942-1946.; 3 folders. (Box 51)
    - Durham, NC (African American), 1943-1945. (Box 51)
    - Edenton, NC, 1943-1947. (Box 51)
    - Fayetteville, NC, 1941-1948.; 3 folders. (Box 51)
    - Fayetteville, NC (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 52)
    - Goldsboro, NC, 1942-1944. (Box 52)
    - Greensboro, NC, 1943-1947. (Box 52)
    - Greensboro, NC (African American), 1943-1947. (Box 52)
    - Hertford, NC, 1945. (Box 52)
    - Jacksonville, NC, 1943-1958.; 2 folders. (Box 52)
    - Jacksonville, NC (African American), 1947. (Box 52)
    - Kinston, NC, 1942-1946. (Box 52)
    - Kinston, NC (African American), 1944-1945. (Box 52)
    - Laurinburg, NC, 1943-1946. (Box 52)
    - Maxton, NC, 1943-1945. (Box 52)
    - Monroe, NC, 1942-1945. (Box 53)
    - Monroe, NC (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 53)
    - Morehead City, NC, 1941-1948.; 4 folders. (Box 80)
    - Morehead City, NC (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 80)
    - Raleigh, NC, 1942-1944.; 2 folders. (Box 53)
    - Raleigh, NC (African American), 1943-1947. (Box 53)
    - Rockingham, NC, 1943-1947. (Box 53)
    - Southport, NC, 1943-1945. (Box 53)
    - Spring Lake, NC, 1941-1945. (Box 53)
    - Swansboro, NC, 1942-1947. (Box 53)
    - Wilmington, NC, 1941-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 53)
    - Wilmington, NC, 1941-1947. (Box 54)
    - Lincoln, NE, 1945-1946. (Box 54)
    - Lincoln, NE (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 54)
    - Omaha, NE (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 79)
    - York, NE, 1943-1945. (Box 54)
    - Manchester, NH, 1942-1946. (Box 54)
    - Manchester, NH (African American), 1942-1946. (Box 54)
    - Eatontown, NJ, 1942-1945. (Box 54)
    - Lakehurst, NJ, 1941-1946. (Box 54)
    - New Brunswick, NJ, 1942-1947.; 3 folders. (Box 79)
    - New Brunswick, NJ, 1942-1947. (Box 80)
    - Red Bank, NJ, 1942-1946. (Box 54)
    - Red Bank, NJ, 1942-1946. (Box 55)
    - Red Bank, NJ (African American), 1941-1945. (Box 55)
    - Stelton, NJ (African American), 1944-1947. (Box 55)
    - Trenton, NJ, 1942-1947.; 2 folders. (Box 55)
    - Trenton, NJ (African American), 1944-1945. (Box 55)
    - Wrightstown, NJ, 1941-1946. (Box 55)
    - Wrightstown, NJ (African American), 1941-1948. (Box 55)
    - Alamogordo, NM, 1949-1958. (Box 55)
    - Hobbs, NM, 1942-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 55)
    - Hobbs, NM (African American), 1942-1945. (Box 55)
    - Tonopah, NV, 1942-1944. (Box 56)
    - Fisher's Island, NY, 1946. (Box 56)
    - Fort Totten, NY, 1953. (Box 56)
    - Geneva, NY, 1943-1946. (Box 56)